Finding Aid for the Lawrence Morton Papers LSC.1522
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Research Material
  - Stravinsky, Programs Relating to
    - Boston Symphony Orchestra (11-12 February)--[All Stravinsky]., 1949. (Box 27)
      Stravinsky conducts Ode, Capriccio (Soulima Stravinsky, piano), Concerto in D for strings and the first concert performance of Orpheus.
    - Stadtische Buhne Heidelberg (17 June)., 1962. (Box 27)
      Stravinsky, Pulcinella.
    - Stadtische Buhne Heidelberg., 1959-60. (Box 27)
      Stravinsky, L'Histoire du soldat.
    - Teatro Eliseo, Roma (14 April)--[All Stravinsky]., 1954. (Box 27)
      It is unclear whether or not the composer conducted. The program included Orpheus, Scherzo ala russe, Four Norwegian moods, Scenes de ballet and The firebird suite [version?].
    - Los Angeles Music Guild (6 January)--[All Stravinsky]., 1962. (Box 27)
      Craft conducts Dumbarton Oaks Concerto, Verlaine Songs, Pribaoutki and Renard. Stravinsky conducts his L'Histoire du soldat' suite.
    - Royal Opera House Covent Garden (16 December)., 1982. (Box 28)
      David Atherton conducts Stravinsky, The rake's progress.
    - Orquesta Sinfonica de Mexico (18 & 20 July)--[All Stravinsky]., 1941. (Box 28)
      Stravinsky conducts Symphony in C, Capriccio (Salvador Ochoa, piano), Pulcinella suite and Divertimento.
    - The Concert Choir at Town Hall (New York--12 January)--[All Stravinsky]., 1954. (Box 28)
      Margaret Hillis conducts Pater Noster, Ave Maria, Mass, Symphony of Psalms, Mavra and Les Noces.
    - Vienna State Opera (4 November)., 1958. (Box 28)
    - La Biennale de Venizia (27 September)., 1960. (Box 28)
      Craft conducts Stravinsky, Monumentum pro Gesualdo and Orpheus.
    - Dusseldorf (6 February)--[All Stravinsky]., 1930. (Box 28)
      Stravinsky conducts Apollon musagetes, Suites I & II for small orchestra, Petrouschka and The firebird suite (1919).
    - St. Louis Symphony (5-6 February)., 1966. (Box 28)
      Craft conducts Brahms-Schoenberg, Piano quartet in g minor. Stravinsky conducts his Variations Aldous Huxley in memoriam (Craft ?), Capriccio (Jocy de Oliveira, pianist) and Pulcinella Suite.
    - La Biennale di Venizia (19 September)--[All Stravinsky]., 1958. (Box 28)
      Oedipus Rex and Le Sacre du Printemps.
    - Columbia Records Concert in Town Hall (20 December)., 1959. (Box 28)
      Premiere of Stravinsky, Epitaphium.
    - New York City Ballet (21 December)--[All Stravinsky]., 1960. (Box 28)
      Apollo, Ebony Concerto, Agon and Firebird (1946).
    - La Biennale di Venizia (23 September)--[All Stravinsky]., 1958. (Box 28)
      Symphonies of wind instruments, In memoriam Dylan Thomas, Vom Himmel hoch...' Variations and Threni.
    - Columbia Records Concert in Town Hall (New York). 10 January., 1960. (Box 28)
      Premiere of Stravinsky, Movements for piano and orchestra.
    - Theatre des Nation (Paris 15 March-13 July)--Paris Festival revue, 1954-60, 1960. (Box 28)
    - Festival D'Automne A Paris (September-December)--Stravinsky., 1980. (Box 28)
    - A Haydn--Stravinsky celebration presented by The Chamber Society of Lincoln Center (13-20 September)., 1981. (Box 28)
    - Musica Viva, Munchen--Series program., 1962-63. (Box 28)
    - Musica Viva Munchen (17 February)., 1956. (Box 28)
      Eugen Jochum conducts Pulcinella.
    - Musica Viva, Munchen (19 November)--[All Stravinsky]., 1963. (Box 28)
      Paul Sacher conducts Monumentum pro Gesualdo, Abraham and Isaac, A sermon, a narrative and a prayer and Symphony in three movements.
    - Sadler's Wells Theater at the Theatre Royal de la Monnai (Brussels 18 April)--[All Stravinsky]., 1960. (Box 28)
      Oedipus Rex conducted by Colin Davis. Le Sacre du Printemps conducted by Andre Vandernoot.
    - Hamburg Opera at the Edinburgh Festival--[All Stravinsky]., 1956. (Box 28)
      Oedipus Rex and Mavra.
    - Los Angeles County Museum (27 June)--[All Stravinsky]., 1954. (Box 28)
      Craft conducts Pastoral, Septet (American radio premiere), Shakespeare Songs (world radio premiere), Tango, Cantata (American radio premiere).
    - New York Concert Symphony Orchestra, Ithica College Choir at Princeton University (8 October)--[All Stravinsky]., 1966. (Box 28)
      Craft conducts Symphonies of wind instruments, Pater noster, Credo (Premiere of rev.version), Ave Maria, Variations Aldous Huxley in memoriam, Mass and premiere of Requiem canticles.
    - Le Choer de la Radio-Television de Belgrade avec le concours de L'Orchestre de Chambre de la Radio Diffusion-Television Francaise. (Box 28)
      Borivoje Simic conducts Stravinsky, Les Noces.
    - Fromm Music Foundation in Town Hall (4 January)., 1959. (Box 28)
      Stravinsky, Threni, also works by Berg.
    - San Francisco Opera (29 October)., 1962. (Box 28)
      Leopold Ludwig conducts The rake's progress.
    - Columbia Records Concert in Town Hall (3 January)., 1960. (Box 28)
      American premiere of Webern 6 pieces opus 6.
    - Los Angeles Music Festival in Association with Monday Evening Concerts. 17 June--[All Stravinsky]., 1957. (Box 28)
      Waxman conducts Greeting Prelude. Craft conducts Symphonies of wind instruments, Canticumsacrum and Agon. A. Huxley speaks. Stravinsky conducts Himmel hoch... and Symphony of psalms.
    - Swarthmore College Orchestra and Chorus (1 May)., 1965. (Box 28)
      Claudio Spies conducts Stravinsky, Introitus.
    - Janssen Symphony at the Wilshire Ebell Theater (22 October)., 1944. (Box 28)
      Stravinsky, Dumbarton Oaks concerto--in L.M.'s hand, mistakenly labeled Los Angeles Premiere.
    - Janssen Symphony at the Wilshire Ebell Theater (8 February)., 1942. (Box 28)
      Stravinsky conducts the premiere of his Danses concertantes, also Pulcinella Suite.
    - London Sinfonietta (17 June)--Igor Stravinsky anniversary concert., 1972. (Box 28)
      Conducted by Elgar Howeth.
    - Santa Fe Opera (17, 19 & 20 July)., 1957. (Box 28)
      Craft conducts The rake's progress.
    - Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra, Wilshire Ebell Theater (3 January)., 1949. (Box 28)
      Harold Byrnes conducts Stravinsky, Dumbarton Oaks Concerto.
    - Los Angeles Music Festival (7 June)--[All Stravinsky]., 1960. (Box 28)
      Stravinsky conducts Mass and Les Noces.
    - Los Angeles Music Festival Program Book (5 June)., 1961. (Box 28)
    - Teatro alla Scala (4 March)., 1980. (Box 28)
      Hans Vonk conducts The rake's progress.
    - Norddeutscher Rundfunk (19 September)--[All Stravinsky]., 1958. (Box 28)
      Stravinsky conducts Oedipus Rex and Le Sacre du Printemps.
    - The Chamber Art Society (11 April)--[All Stravinsky]., 1948. (Box 28)
      Stravinsky conducts the first concert performance of Symphonies of wind instruments (1947 version), also Danses concertantes and Capriccio. Craft conducts Symphony in C.
    - Orquesta Sinfonica Venezuela (19 April)., 1953. (Box 28)
      Stravinsky conducts Glinka, Russlan and Ludmilla overture, Tchaikovsky, Symphony no.2 and his The firebird suite (n.d.).
    - Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra, Royce Hall (15 January)--[All Stravinsky]., 1952. (Box 28)
      Stravinsky conducts Octet, Histoire du soldat suite, Dumbarton Oaks concerto and Danses concertantes.
    - Berlin Festwoche--Igor Strawinsky--Austellung., 1980. (Box 30)
    - Ville de Strasbourg Deuxieme Exposition Europeenne--Les ballets russes de Serge de Diaghilev., 1969 15 Mai-15 Septembre. (Box 60)
      Ville de Strasbourg.
    - League of composer programs and scores., Photographic negatives and prints. (Box 65)
    - The University of Utah Department of Music (20-22 April)--The Stravinsky centennial., 1982. (Box 67)
    - Boston Symphony Orchestra 1972-1973 (12-13 January). (Box 67)
      Salute to Diaghilev--2 Spectrum Concerts--M.T. Thomas.
    - The Stravinsky Centenary Festival at the Hollywood Bowl (1, 3, 8 and 10 July)., 1982.; 2 copies. (Box 67)
      Flyer with poster.
    - A Haydn--Stravinsky celebration presented by The Chamber Music Society of Lincoln Center (13-20 September)., 1981. (Box 67)
    - International Stravinsky Symposium/University of California at San Diego--Stravinsky 100., 1982. (Box 67)
    - 30. Berliner festwochen 80--Opus Strawinsky festakademe., 1980. (Box 67)
    - 30. Berliner festwochen 80--Geburtstagsparty fur Strawinsky., 1980. (Box 67)
    - New York City Opera--The rake's progress (September 30)., 1984. (Box 85)
      Conducted by Christopher Keene.
    - Theatre National de L'Opera--Hommage a Diaghilev., 1972. (Box 91)
    - Ojai Festival--Programs., 1948-1970. (Box 96)
    - Los Angeles County Museum of Art--Music programs., 1965-1976. (Box 96)
    - Los Angeles County Museum of Art--Music programs., 1977-1982. (Box 97)
    - Ojai Festivals--Programs., 1971-1985. (Box 97)
  - Stravinsky, Vera
    - Morton correspondence relating to loan of Vera Stravinsky paintings to exhibit in Minneapolis., 1985. (Box 6)
    - Craft, Robert--Where's Vera? She's painting., 1972. (Box 10)
      Photographed by Arnold Newman.
      Saturday Review (26 February): 45-49.
    - Stravinsky, Vera--Letter to a cousin in Moscow., 1964. (Box 34)
      The London Magazine (August) 4(5): 49-55.
    - Stravinsky, Vera--Fantastic cities and other paintings., 1977. (Box 35)
      Boston: David R. Godine.
      Inscribed by the author: To Dear Lawrence my old friend with love Vera Stravinsky 1979.
    - Stravinsky, Vera. (Box 68)
    - Craft, Robert--Where's Vera? She's painting., 1972. (Box 81)
    - Craft, Robert--La Belle russe., 1978. (Box 81)
      Vogue (October): 358-59, 396.
    - Aronson, M. l--Vera Stravinsky: Stravinsky in pictures and documents., 1979. (Box 81)
      Interview 9(4): 53-58.
    - Craft, Robert--Vera Stravinsky., 1983. (Box 123)
      New York Review of Books (17 March): 8-12.
    - Six works on canvas. (Box 125)
    - Stravinsky, Vera--Three Oils on Canvas., 1958, n.d. (Box 126)
- Musical Writings
  - Stravinsky Items. Publication Material. Programs, 1981-1982 (Box 136, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Publication Material. Clippings and Magazines., 1949-1985 (Box 136, Folder 2)
  - Modern Music. Publication Material. Offprints., 1943-1946 (Box 136, Folder 3)
  - Hollywood Quarterly Publication Material. Offprints., mid 1940s (Box 136, Folder 4)
  - Film Composers in America. Compiled and Edited by Clifford Murray, 1953 (Box 136, Folder 5)
  - Notes (MLA) Publication Material. Clippings., circa 1940-1959 (Box 136, Folder 7)
  - Film Music Notes Publication Material. Copies of Journal., 1948-1951 (Box 136, Folder 8)